<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Arcanatron</name>
        <description>5e homebrew</description>
        <author url="https://dnd-5e-homebrew.tumblr.com/post/147044434296/arcanatron-race-by-geekfirelabs">geekfirelabs</author>
        <update version="0.0.4">
            <file name="race-arcanatron.xml"  url="https://github.com/Osnil/My-Homebrew-Collection/blob/master/race-arcanatron.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>

    <element name="Arcanatron" type="Race" source="geekfirelabs" id="ID_GFL_RACE_ARCANATROn">
        <description>
            <h4>HISTORY</h4>
            <p>Forged in a foreign world without magic, the arcanatrons are the youngest race in Newterra. 100 years ago, druing an explosion of apocalyptic proportions, the veils that separated the multiverse from other worlds simultaneously tore open. Within seconds, the world righted itself and the rifts stitched themselves back together, but the damage had already been done. Entire cities had fused with mountains that hadn't been there moments before, their denizens encased in permeating tombs of stone. Ocreans became infertile wastelands. Jungel sprang from what once had been arid desert. And the arcanatrons, shunted violently from their home world, found themselves in an alien land with no explanation, no direction, and no masters. What was more, they slowly began to realize that the new sensations they were collectively experiencing were, in fact, free thoughts and feelings. And so, like children, they stumbled into Newterra and began to discover their new world through eyes full of wonder. </p>
            <h4>UNWELCOME NEWCOMERS</h4>
            <p>Though arcanatrons have striven to integrate with the other races, even going so far as to claim an unwanted region of inhospitable land as their new home, but they are still met with discrimination and sometimes outright hatred. To many denizens of Newterra, arcanatrons are a bitter reminder of the cataclysimc event hat ripped the fabric of the world a century ago. in the earliest years after the Convergence, there were a few attempts to enslave the arcanatrons while they were still in a vulnerable state. Some complied, choosing servitude over the sudden and daunting anxiety of autonomy. But most, since their Awakening, most arcanatrons recognize no master save for themselves.</p>
            <h4>EXTERNAL AESTHETICS</h4
            <p>Arcanatrons are bi-pedal and humanoid in shape and stature. Composite plates of sturdy metal make up their forms, hiding a complex system of internal wiring and tubes. In an ongoing quest for self-identity, each arcanatron strives to make sure its external appearance is unique. Some choose to take on the smooth, ethereal features of the elves, while others prefer harsh, geometric edges. On rare occasion an arcanatron will outfit itself with animalistic features, such as a black metal raven's head or brass scales meant to mirror those of a dragon's. These are few and far between, however, and the practice is seen as a little eccentric, even withing the arcanatron community. At the core of each arcanatron rests a crystallized hunk of pure mana energy, which acts as their life force. This mystical battery is a self-sustained form of consistent energy and never needs recharging. It can, however, become damaged or corrupted, rendering an arcanatron inert or - for all intents and purposes - lifeless.</p>
            <h4>ARCANATRON NAMES</h4>
            <p>As a race, arcanatrons have not quite mastered the art of naming. In their language, a name is usually comprised of a series of 1's and 0's, making 'I's and 'O's popular choices within their naming conventions. Because so many of these names look and sound alike, an arcanatron might choose a surname to attempt to add fruther distinction. These surnames oftentimes reflect how the arcanatron sees itself as an individual, something they like, or something they strive to be. The names are always spoken in Common in an effort to convey who they are to other races, but usually just leads to more confusion and, usually, a nickname.</p>
            <p>
                <span class="feature">Example Names:</span> Ios, Oi, Clio, Lio, Ois, Diodri, Eion, Nio, Niino, Miono, Sioto, Uio, Viovi<br/>
                <span class="feature">Example Surnames:</span> Pale Blue Dot (Dotty), Remembers When (Remy), Wanders Through World (Wanda), Stays At Home (Homer), Woven Under A Waking Moon(Waximus), Black Fox (Fox), Beautiful Badger Going Over the Hill (Badger)<br/>
            </p>
            <h4>HOMUNCULUS TRAITS</h4>
            <p>Homunculi were created by a large merchant empire called Xerxes.</p>
            <p>
                <span class="feature">Ability Score Increase.</span>Your Charisma score increases by 2, and your Dexterity or Strength score increases by 1.<br/>
                <span class="feature">Age.</span>Homunculi being living constructs are unable to age from the point they are created at. Otherwise they are immortal.<br/>
                <span class="feature">Alignment.</span>Being created, homunculi are soulless beings so they start out completely neutral, but innately tend towards a chaotic alignment with a natural curiosity of the world they were brought into.<br/>
                <span class="feature">Size.</span>Homunculi are the same size and build as humans. Your size is Medium.<br/>
                <span class="feature">Speed.</span>Your base walking speed is 30 feet.<br/>
                <span class="feature">Natural Liar.</span>Homunculi live through lying about their origins. You have proficiency in the Deception skill.<br/>
                <span class="feature">Lifestone.</span>Homunculi have a Lifestone as their core that grants them excelled healing. After a short or long rest you gain temporary hit points equal to your level + your Constitution mod. Also if you lose any part of your body, it will regenerate over the course of a day. Any spells that would cause the caster to take damage deal half that rounded up.<br/>
                <span class="feature">Living Construct.</span>You are a living construct. You do not need to eat, drink, breathe, or sleep. You never make Endurance checks to resist the effect of starvation, thirst, or suffocation. All other conditions and effects affect you normally.<br/>
                <span class="feature">Arcane Origins.</span>You know the Prestidigitation cantrip. Once you reach 3rd level, you can cast the Hex spell once per day as a 2nd-level spell. Once you reach 5th level, you can also cast the Alter Self once per day. Charisma is your spellcasting ability for these spells.<br/>
                <span class="feature">Languages.</span>You can speak, read, and write Common and one extra language of your choice. Homunculi typically learn the languages of other peoples they deal with, including obscure dialects.<br/>
            </p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <setters>
            <set name="names" type="male">Courage, Empathy, Justice, Piety, Gluttony, Greed, Wrath, Pride</set>
            <set name="names" type="female">Faith, Harmony, Hope, Joy, Charity, Envy, Lust, Sloth</set>
            <set name="names-format">{{name}}</set>
        </setters>
        <rules>
            <stat name="charisma" value="2"/>
            <select type="Racial Trait" name="Ability Score Increase (Homunculus)" supports="ID_WIKI_RACIAL_TRAIT_HOMUNCULUS_STRENGTH|ID_WIKI_RACIAL_TRAIT_HOMUNCULUS_DEXTERITY" />
            <stat name="innate speed" value="30" bonus="base"/>
            <grant type="Size" id="ID_SIZE_MEDIUM" />
            <grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_COMMON" />
            <select type="Language" name="Language (Homunculus)" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_WIKI_RACIAL_TRAIT_HOMUNCULUS_NATURAL_LIAR" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_WIKI_RACIAL_TRAIT_HOMUNCULUS_LIFESTONE" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_WIKI_RACIAL_TRAIT_HOMUNCULUS_LIVING_CONSTRUCT" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_WIKI_RACIAL_TRAIT_HOMUNCULUS_ARCANE_ORIGINS" />
        </rules>
    </element>

    <element name="Natural Liar" type="Racial Trait" source="D&amp;D Wiki" id="ID_WIKI_RACIAL_TRAIT_HOMUNCULUS_NATURAL_LIAR">
        <description>
            <p>Homunculi live through lying about their origins. You have proficiency in the Deception skill.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description>Homunculi live through lying about their origins. You have proficiency in the Deception skill.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_DECEPTION" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Lifestone" type="Racial Trait" source="D&amp;D Wiki" id="ID_WIKI_RACIAL_TRAIT_HOMUNCULUS_LIFESTONE">
        <description>
            <p>Homunculi have a Lifestone as their core that grants them excelled healing. After a short or long rest you gain temporary hit points equal to your level + your Constitution mod. Also if you lose any part of your body, it will regenerate over the course of a day. Any spells that would cause the caster to take damage deal half that rounded up.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>After a short or long rest you gain {{lifestone:hp:temp}} temporary hit points. Also if you lose any part of your body, it will regenerate over the course of a day. Any spells that would cause the caster to take damage deal half that rounded up.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="lifestone:hp:temp" value="level" />
            <stat name="lifestone:hp:temp" value="constitution:modifier" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Living Construct" type="Racial Trait" source="D&amp;D Wiki" id="ID_WIKI_RACIAL_TRAIT_HOMUNCULUS_LIVING_CONSTRUCT">
        <description>
            <p>You are a living construct. You do not need to eat, drink, breathe, or sleep. You never make Endurance checks to resist the effect of starvation, thirst, or suffocation. All other conditions and effects affect you normally.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You do not need to eat, drink, breathe, or sleep. You never make Endurance checks to resist the effect of starvation, thirst, or suffocation.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Arcane Origins" type="Racial Trait" source="D&amp;D Wiki" id="ID_WIKI_RACIAL_TRAIT_HOMUNCULUS_ARCANE_ORIGINS">
        <description>
            <p>You know the Prestidigitation cantrip. Once you reach 3rd level, you can cast the Hex spell once per day as a 2nd-level spell. Once you reach 5th level, you can also cast the Alter Self once per day. Charisma is your spellcasting ability for these spells.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You know the Prestidigitation cantrip. (Charisma)</description>
            <description level="3">You know the Prestidigitation cantrip. You can cast the Hex spell once per day as a 2nd-level spell.(Charisma)</description>
            <description level="5">You know the Prestidigitation cantrip. You can cast the Hex spell once per day as a 2nd-level spell. You can also cast the Alter Self once per day. (Charisma)</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PRESTIDIGITATION" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HEX" level="3" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ALTER_SELF" level="5" />
        </rules>
    </element>


  <element name="Ability Score Increase (Strength)" type="Racial Trait" source="D&amp;D Wiki" id="ID_WIKI_RACIAL_TRAIT_HOMUNCULUS_STRENGTH">
    <supports>Homunculus</supports>
    <requirements />
    <description>
      <p>Your Strength increases by 1.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet display="false" />
    <rules>
      <stat name="strength" value="1"/>
    </rules>
  </element>
  <element name="Ability Score Increase (Dexterity)" type="Racial Trait" source="D&amp;D Wiki" id="ID_WIKI_RACIAL_TRAIT_HOMUNCULUS_DEXTERITY">
    <supports>Homunculus</supports>
    <requirements />
    <description>
      <p>Your Dexterity increases by 1.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet display="false" />
    <rules>
      <stat name="dexterity" value="1"/>
    </rules>
  </element>
</elements>
