<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Arcanatron</name>
        <description>5e homebrew</description>
        <author url="https://dnd-5e-homebrew.tumblr.com/post/147044434296/arcanatron-race-by-geekfirelabs">geekfirelabs</author>
        <update version="0.0.4">
            <file name="race-arcanatron.xml"  url="https://github.com/Osnil/My-Homebrew-Collection/blob/master/race-arcanatron.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>

    <element name="Arcanatron" type="Race" source="geekfirelabs" id="ID_GFL_RACE_ARCANATRON">
        <description>
            <h4>HISTORY</h4>
            <p>Forged in a foreign world without magic, the arcanatrons are the youngest race in Newterra. 100 years ago, druing an explosion of apocalyptic proportions, the veils that separated the multiverse from other worlds simultaneously tore open. Within seconds, the world righted itself and the rifts stitched themselves back together, but the damage had already been done. Entire cities had fused with mountains that hadn't been there moments before, their denizens encased in permeating tombs of stone. Ocreans became infertile wastelands. Jungel sprang from what once had been arid desert. And the arcanatrons, shunted violently from their home world, found themselves in an alien land with no explanation, no direction, and no masters. What was more, they slowly began to realize that the new sensations they were collectively experiencing were, in fact, free thoughts and feelings. And so, like children, they stumbled into Newterra and began to discover their new world through eyes full of wonder. </p>
            <h4>UNWELCOME NEWCOMERS</h4>
            <p>Though arcanatrons have striven to integrate with the other races, even going so far as to claim an unwanted region of inhospitable land as their new home, but they are still met with discrimination and sometimes outright hatred. To many denizens of Newterra, arcanatrons are a bitter reminder of the cataclysimc event hat ripped the fabric of the world a century ago. in the earliest years after the Convergence, there were a few attempts to enslave the arcanatrons while they were still in a vulnerable state. Some complied, choosing servitude over the sudden and daunting anxiety of autonomy. But most, since their Awakening, most arcanatrons recognize no master save for themselves.</p>
            <h4>EXTERNAL AESTHETICS</h4>
            <p>Arcanatrons are bi-pedal and humanoid in shape and stature. Composite plates of sturdy metal make up their forms, hiding a complex system of internal wiring and tubes. In an ongoing quest for self-identity, each arcanatron strives to make sure its external appearance is unique. Some choose to take on the smooth, ethereal features of the elves, while others prefer harsh, geometric edges. On rare occasion an arcanatron will outfit itself with animalistic features, such as a black metal raven's head or brass scales meant to mirror those of a dragon's. These are few and far between, however, and the practice is seen as a little eccentric, even withing the arcanatron community. At the core of each arcanatron rests a crystallized hunk of pure mana energy, which acts as their life force. This mystical battery is a self-sustained form of consistent energy and never needs recharging. It can, however, become damaged or corrupted, rendering an arcanatron inert or - for all intents and purposes - lifeless.</p>
            <h4>ARCANATRON NAMES</h4>
            <p>As a race, arcanatrons have not quite mastered the art of naming. In their language, a name is usually comprised of a series of 1's and 0's, making 'I's and 'O's popular choices within their naming conventions. Because so many of these names look and sound alike, an arcanatron might choose a surname to attempt to add fruther distinction. These surnames oftentimes reflect how the arcanatron sees itself as an individual, something they like, or something they strive to be. The names are always spoken in Common in an effort to convey who they are to other races, but usually just leads to more confusion and, usually, a nickname.</p>
            <p>
                <span class="feature">Example Names:</span> Ios, Oi, Clio, Lio, Ois, Diodri, Eion, Nio, Niino, Miono, Sioto, Uio, Viovi<br/>
                <span class="feature">Example Surnames:</span> Pale Blue Dot (Dotty), Remembers When (Remy), Wanders Through World (Wanda), Stays At Home (Homer), Woven Under A Waking Moon(Waximus), Black Fox (Fox), Beautiful Badger Going Over the Hill (Badger)<br/>
            </p>
            <h4>ARCANATRON TRAITS</h4>
            <p>
                <span class="feature">Ability Score Increase.</span>Your Constitution increases by 1, and your Intelligence increases by 1.<br/>
                <span class="feature">Age.</span>Theoretically, an Arcanatron can live indefinitely, for as long as its mana core holds out. It is possible for the creators of the specific Arcanatron to manually set a lifespan of their choice, for whatever reason, however this is not the norm.<br/>
                <span class="feature">Alignment.</span>Arcanatrons were built in a world without magic and originally had no innate understanding of good or evil. They were robotic slaves to their masters, programmed to carry out specific tasks without question. During the Convergence, the exposure to both the raw magical energies of creation and destruction infused the arcanatrons with sentience, free will and, perhaps, with souls. They are inclined toward neutrality, but circumstance and age all play a role in individual alignment.<br/>
                <span class="feature">Size.</span>Though very few arcanatrons look alike, they tend to favor modifying themselves to mimic human features.  Your size is Medium.<br/>
                <span class="feature">Speed.</span>Your base walking speed is 30 feet.<br/>
                <span class="feature">Darkvision.</span> You have superior vision in dark and dim conditions. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of grey.<br/>
                <span class="feature">Living Construct.</span>Even though you were constructed, you are humanoid. You do not need to breathe, eat or drink, but you can ingest food or drink if you wish. You still benefit from the effects of consumable spells and magic items such as heroes feast and potions.<br/>
                <span class="feature">Arcanatron Resilience.</span>You have advantage on saving throws against poison and have resistance to poison damage.<br/>
                <span class="feature">Unsleeping Sentinel.</span>Arcanatrons don't need to sleep. Instead, they settle into a resting state, remaining semiconscious for 4 hours each day. While in this rest state, you are fully aware of your surroundings. After resting in this way, you gain the same benefit that a human does from 8 hours of sleep.<br/>
                <span class="feature">Self Stabilizing.</span>Upon reaching 0 hit points, your mana core enters an emergency self-preservation mode and you slip into an inert state. You can be spooled up again through healing magic or by being repaired. You have advantage on death saving throws. <br />
                <span class="feature">Languages.</span><br/>You can speak, read, and write Common, Ohwon, and one other language of your choice.<br />
                <span class="feature">Models.</span>Several submodels of Arcanatrons are found among the worlds of Dungeons and Dragons. Choose one of these models.
            </p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <stat name="intelligence" value="1"/>
            <stat name="constitution" value="1"/>
            <stat name="innate speed" value="30" bonus="base"/>
            <grant type="Size" id="ID_SIZE_MEDIUM" />
            <grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_COMMON" />
            <grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_OHWON" />
            <select type="Language" name="Language (Arcanatron)" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_GEEKFIRELABS_RACIAL_TRAIT_ARCANATRON_LIVING_CONSTRUCT" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_GEEKFIRELABS_RACIAL_TRAIT_ARCANATRON_RESILIENCE" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_GEEKFIRELABS_RACIAL_TRAIT_UNSLEEPING_SENTINEL" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_GEEKFIRELABS_RACIAL_TRAIT_ARCANATRON_SELF_STABILIZING" />
        </rules>
    </element>

    <element name="Living Construct" type="Racial Trait" source="geekfirelabs" id="ID_GEEKFIRELABS_RACIAL_TRAIT_ARCANATRON_LIVING_CONSTRUCT">
        <description>
            <p>Even though you were constructed, you are humanoid. You do not need to breathe, eat or drink, but you can ingest food or drink if you wish. You still benefit from the effects of consumable spells and magic items such as heroes feast and potions.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="true">
            <description>You do not need to breathe, eat or drink, and take benefits from healing spells and consumable items.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Arcanatron Resilience" type="Racial Trait" source="geekfirelabs" id="ID_GEEKFIRELABS_RACIAL_TRAIT_ARCANTRON_ARCANATRON_RESILIENCE">
        <description>
            <p>You have advantage on saving throws against poison and have resistance to poison damage.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You have advantage on saving throws against poison and have resistance to poison damage.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Unsleeping Sentinel" type="Racial Trait" source="geekfirelabs" id="ID_GEEKFIRELABS_RACIAL_TRAIT_ARCANTRON_UNSLEEPING_SENTINEL">
        <description>
            <p>Arcanatrons don't need to sleep. Instead, they settle into a resting state, remaining semiconscious for 4 hours each day. While in this rest state, you are fully aware of your surroundings. After resting in this way, you gain the same benefit that a human does from 8 hours of sleep.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You only need to rest four hours a day to benefit a long rest.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Self-Stabilizing" type="Racial Trait" source="geekfirelabs" id="ID_ARCANATRON_SELF_STABILIZING">
        <description>
            <p>You have advantage on death saving throws</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You have advantage on Death Saving Throws</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
</elements>
